IMRAN AFTAB

About Me

Experienced Graphic Designer adept in creating powerful visual designs using digital illustrations, images, and typography. Committed to helping clients shape their brand identity through the use of compelling graphic designs. Accustomed to collaborating with other creative professionals to achieve project goals.

Contact

Address 99 Tolpits Lane

WD18 6NT Watford Herts

United Kingdom

E-mail mr.imran92@hotmail.com

Mobile 0044-7519255886

Website www.fiverr.com/logo_des1gner

Linkdin linkedin.com/in/imran-aftab-ab3559107

Skills

- Graphic Design
- Branding (Logo, Stationery, Brochure, Labels, UI and Web design)
- Web development
- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- Git
- Printing
- Problem solving
- Creativity
- Communication
- Computing/IT
- Social Media Marketing
- Administration

Education

Bachelor in Business Administration (Hons)
Mirpur University Of Science And Technology 2010 - 2014

Higher Secondary School Certificate
Cresent Model College, Mipur AJK 2008 - 2010

Certificates

Training Certificate in Wordpress and Digital Marketing digiskills.pk Feb 2021 - May 2021

_ . . _ . . _ . . _ . .

Training Certificate in Freelancing and Graphic Design digiskills.pk Oct 2020 - Jan 2021

Experience

Graphic Designer

Minuteman Press Watford March 2022 - Present

- Gathering customer requirements, estimating effort for design, print and provide quotation as per request.
- Participating in Kickoffs meetings to prioritize deliverables adhering to the deadlines.
- Designing media like logos, flyers, posters, books, promotional catalogues, menus, stickers, labels and many more customizable products.
- Enhancing image quality, matching color modes and handling customer files to make them print ready.
- Managing end to end lifecycle from product designing, printing and finishing the product.
- · Hands on experience on Fiery and Efi software for digital printing.
- Building rapport with customers by assurance quality delivery to customers and matching their expectations.

Customer Service Advisor Sitel Group July 2021 - March 2022

- Acting as a level 3 and 2 agents in Test and Trace Programme working on behalf of Public Health England/NHS.
- Calling up confirmed contacts of COVID-19 cases.
- Calling up confirmed cases of COVID-19.
- Capturing the data of these contacts and cases via a questionnaire.
- Providing advice on Self-isolation requirements, What to do if they become unwell, Advice on welfare matters.
- Making isolation follow up calls to contacts and cases of COVID-19.
- Ensuring that citizens have full understanding of their legal obligation to isolate.

Expertise

- Adobe illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- · Adobe Indesign
- Adobe XD
- Adobe Dimension
- · Adobe After Effects
- Wordpress
- Canva
- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft Powerpoint

Languages

- English
- Urdu

Interests

- Technology
- Social Media
- Football
- Reading
- Badminton

Experience continued

- Providing isolation support and signposting contacts/cases to available resources.
- Utilise the FAQs for any questions contacts/cases may have.
- Working within a team and escalating the challenging situations to level 1 clinical lead.

Freelance Graphic Designer Self-Employed Dec 2015 - Present

- Creating a wide range of projects, often using skills outside of the graphic design realm.
- Responsible for keeping up with the latest design trends and software needed to complete the task. This includes, but is not limited to, color schemes, fonts and typography, shape and form, and layout.
- Outside of typical design skills, I also have been asked to utilize copywriting, copy editing, photography, social media, sales, and marketing skills.
- Flexible with the ability to take direction, work independently and set creative priorities.
- Executing design decisions, sell concepts, and ensure client expectations are met.
- Translating customer ideas to original artwork for long and short term projects.
- Designing logos and other brand identity elements for start-up and established companies.
- Providing brand and marketing consultancy to clients and designing logos and marketing collateral based on client instructions.
- Providing comprehensive graphic design and marketing services to a range of clients.
- Providing support and advice to different clients on a wide range of graphic design processes.
- Translating customer ideas to original artwork for long and short term projects.

Admin Assistant (Part time) Affinity Legal (Formerly Law Assist Limited - Watford) March - June 2021

- · Designing company branding and marketing collateral.
- Assisting with admin duties for a law company specialising in legal advice and management consultancy.
- Duties include file and matter management i.e. file opening and closing.
- Completed data entry and maintained clients record.
- Answered and managed incoming and outgoing calls while recording accurate messages.